<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Alex_Wang</title>
        <link>https://forest293.github.io/</link>
        <description>Hugo theme - LoveIt</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><managingEditor>wcl934420513@163.com (Alex_Wang)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>wcl934420513@163.com (Alex_Wang)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://forest293.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_9 ：Models for count outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_9-models-for-count-outcomes/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_9-models-for-count-outcomes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Count variables record how many times something has happened. Examples include the number of patients, hospitalizations, daily homicides, theater visits, international conflicts, beverages consumed, industrial injuries, soccer goals scored, new companies, and arrests by police. Although the linear regression model has often been applied to count outcomes, these estimates can be inconsistent or inefficient. In some cases, the linear regression model can provide reasonable results; however, it is much safer]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_8 ：Models for nominal outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_8-models-for-nominal-outcomes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_8-models-for-nominal-outcomes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An outcome is nominal when the categories are assumed to be unordered. For example, marital status can be grouped nominally into the categories of divorced, never married, married, or widowed. Occupations might be organized as professional, white collar, blue collar, craft, and menial. Other examples include reasons for leaving the parents&rsquo; home, the organizational context of scientific work such as industry, government, and academia, and the choice of language in]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_7 ：Models for ordinal outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_7-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_7-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ordinal variables are often coded as consecutive integers from 1 to the number of categories. Perhaps because of this coding, it is tempting to analyze ordinal outcomes with the linear regression model (LRM). However, an ordinal dependent variable violates the assumptions of the LRM, which can lead to incorrect conclusions, as demonstrated strikingly by McKelvey and Zavoina (1975, 117) and Winship and Mare (1984, 521-523). With ordinal outcomes, it is]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_6 ：Models for binary outcomes——Interpretation</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_6-models-for-binary-outcomesinterpretation-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_6-models-for-binary-outcomesinterpretation-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The challenge of interpreting results, then, is to find a summary of how changes in the independent variables are associated with changes in the outcome that best reflects critical substantive processes without overwhelming yourself or your readers with distracting detail. **Using odds ratios to interpret the logit model is very common but rarely is it sufficient for understanding the results of the model. Nonetheless, it is important to understand what]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_5 ：Models for binary outcomes Estimation, testing, and fit</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_5-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_5-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This chapter focuses on the two most often used models for binary outcomes, the binary logit and binary probit models, referred to jointly as the binary regression model (BRM). The BRM allows a researcher to explore how each explanatory variable affects the probability of the event occurring. The BRM is also the foundation from which more complex models for ordinal, nominal, and count models are derived. Ordinal and nominal regression]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_4 ：Methods of interpretation</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_4-methods-of-interpretation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_4-methods-of-interpretation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[introduce methods of interpretation that will be used throughout the rest of the book. Models for categorical outcomes are nonlinear, and this nonlinearity is th e fundamental challenge th at must be addressed for effective interpretation. Most simply, this means th at you cannot effectively interpret your model by presenting a list of the estimated parameters. Instead, we believe that the most effective way to interpret these models is by]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_3 ：Estimation, testing, and fit</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_3-estimation-testing-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_3-estimation-testing-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Reviews Stata commands for fitting models,testing hypotheses,and computing measures of model fit* Our book deals with what we think are the most fundamental and useful cross-sectional regression models for categorical and count outcomes: binary logit and probit, ordinal logit and probit, multinomial logit, Poisson regression, and negative binomial regression. We also explore several less common models, such as the stereotype logistic regression model and the zero-inflated and zero-truncated count models.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Chapter19 ：Complex survey data</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/19.chapter19complex-survey-data/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 06:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/19.chapter19complex-survey-data/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The chapter briefly illustrates the mechanics of using these commands in the context of a complex survey The example dataset used in this chapter is the nhanes2.dta dataset. This is one of the Stata example datasets and is used via the Internet with the webuse command, shown below. 1 2 webuse nhanes2 svyset The svyset command has already been used to declare the design for this survey, naming the primary]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Chapter18 ：Nonlinear models</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/18.chapter18nonlinear-models/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/18.chapter18nonlinear-models/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The chapter begins with a discussion of logistic regression models(most detailed) 1 Binary logistic regression 1.1 A logistic model with one categorical predictor Let’s consider a simple logistic regression model that predicts whether a person smokes (smoke) by the person’s self-reported social class (class). The variable class is a categorical variable that is coded: 1 = lower class, 2]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Chapter17 ：Time as a categorical predictor</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/17.chapter17time-as-a-categorical-predictor/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/17.chapter17time-as-a-categorical-predictor/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This chapter considers models where time is treated as a categorical variable The models presented in this chapter will use the mixed command to fit a model that is a hybrid of a traditional repeated-measures analysis of variance (ANOVA) and a mixed model. Like the repeated-measures ANOVA, there will be one fixed intercept (rather than having random intercepts that we commonly see when using the mixed command). By specifying the]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
