<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Alex_Wang</title>
        <link>https://forest293.github.io/</link>
        <description>Hugo theme - LoveIt</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-CN</language><managingEditor>wcl934420513@163.com (Alex_Wang)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>wcl934420513@163.com (Alex_Wang)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate>
            <atom:link href="https://forest293.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <item>
    <title>[Multilevel  Longitudinal Models] Chapter 2 ：Random-intercept models with covariates</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-3-random-intercept-models-with-covariates/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-3-random-intercept-models-with-covariates/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In this chapter, we extend the variance-components models introduced in the previous chapter by including observed explanatory variables or covariates $x$ .]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Multilevel  Longitudinal Models] Chapter 2 ：Variance-components models</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-2-variance-components-models/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-2-variance-components-models/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1 Introduction In this chapter, we consider the simple situation of clustered data without covariates or explanatory variables. For this setting, we introduce a two-level linear model which we refer to as a variance-components model. Other names for this model include one-way random-effects ANOVA or unconditional hierarchical linear model (where “unconditional” refers to not including and]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Multilevel  Longitudinal Models] Chapter 1 ：Review of linear regression</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-1-review-of-linear-regression/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 23:45:40 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-1-review-of-linear-regression/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1 Introduction The regression models considered here are essential building blocks for multilevel models. Although linear multilevel or mixed models for continuous responses are sometimes viewed from an ANOVA perspective, the regression perspective is beneficial because it is easily generalizable to binary and other types of responses. Furthermore, the Stata commands for multilevel modeling follow a regression syntax. Even experienced regression modelers are likely to benefit from reading this chapter]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Multilevel  Longitudinal Models] Introduction</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-0-introduction/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter-0-introduction/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Level-1 units within the same level-2 unit or cluster tend to be more similar to each other than to units in other clusters. One reason for this is that units do not end up in the same cluster by chance but through some mechanism that may be related to their characteristics. For instance, which schools children go to is influenced by their family background through place of residence or parental]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_9 ：Models for count outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_9-models-for-count-outcomes/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_9-models-for-count-outcomes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Count variables record how many times something has happened. Examples include the number of patients, hospitalizations, daily homicides, theater visits, international conflicts, beverages consumed, industrial injuries, soccer goals scored, new companies, and arrests by police. Although the linear regression model has often been applied to count outcomes, these estimates can be inconsistent or inefficient. In some cases, the linear regression model can provide reasonable results; however, it is much safer]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_8 ：Models for nominal outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_8-models-for-nominal-outcomes/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_8-models-for-nominal-outcomes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[An outcome is nominal when the categories are assumed to be unordered. For example, marital status can be grouped nominally into the categories of divorced, never married, married, or widowed. Occupations might be organized as professional, white collar, blue collar, craft, and menial. Other examples include reasons for leaving the parents&rsquo; home, the organizational context of scientific work such as industry, government, and academia, and the choice of language in]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_7 ：Models for ordinal outcomes</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_7-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_7-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ordinal variables are often coded as consecutive integers from 1 to the number of categories. Perhaps because of this coding, it is tempting to analyze ordinal outcomes with the linear regression model (LRM). However, an ordinal dependent variable violates the assumptions of the LRM, which can lead to incorrect conclusions, as demonstrated strikingly by McKelvey and Zavoina (1975, 117) and Winship and Mare (1984, 521-523). With ordinal outcomes, it is]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_6 ：Models for binary outcomes——Interpretation</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_6-models-for-binary-outcomesinterpretation-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_6-models-for-binary-outcomesinterpretation-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The challenge of interpreting results, then, is to find a summary of how changes in the independent variables are associated with changes in the outcome that best reflects critical substantive processes without overwhelming yourself or your readers with distracting detail. **Using odds ratios to interpret the logit model is very common but rarely is it sufficient for understanding the results of the model. Nonetheless, it is important to understand what]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_5 ：Models for binary outcomes Estimation, testing, and fit</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_5-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_5-models-for-binary-outcomes-estimation-testing-and-fit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This chapter focuses on the two most often used models for binary outcomes, the binary logit and binary probit models, referred to jointly as the binary regression model (BRM). The BRM allows a researcher to explore how each explanatory variable affects the probability of the event occurring. The BRM is also the foundation from which more complex models for ordinal, nominal, and count models are derived. Ordinal and nominal regression]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>[Categorical Dependent Var] Chapter_4 ：Methods of interpretation</title>
    <link>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_4-methods-of-interpretation/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 16:29:41 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Alex_Wang</author>
    <guid>https://forest293.github.io/chapter_4-methods-of-interpretation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[introduce methods of interpretation that will be used throughout the rest of the book. Models for categorical outcomes are nonlinear, and this nonlinearity is th e fundamental challenge th at must be addressed for effective interpretation. Most simply, this means th at you cannot effectively interpret your model by presenting a list of the estimated parameters. Instead, we believe that the most effective way to interpret these models is by]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
